<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Philipp C. Baecker</title><link>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Philipp C. Baecker</description><image><url>https://www.pcbaecker.com/papermod-cover.png</url><link>https://www.pcbaecker.com/papermod-cover.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloudflare with full encryption in strict mode</title><link>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/cloudflare-full-encryption-strict-mode/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/cloudflare-full-encryption-strict-mode/</guid><description>When using cloudflare to manage your domains, in most cases you will want to use cloudflare as a proxy. That means all traffic goes through the cloudflare network before reaching your server. That method has some benefits like the SSL-Certificates are created and managed by cloudflare and you can apply the manifold functions (e.g. CDN, Zero Trust, &amp;hellip;) from cloudflare to your network.
While it is fairly easy to connect cloudflare to your server over http (encryption mode off or flexible) it is not secure.</description></item><item><title>Github actions selfhosted runner on kubernetes</title><link>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/github-selfhosted-runner-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/github-selfhosted-runner-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Using Github&amp;rsquo;s CI tool Github Actions can be very useful for projects that are already hosted on Github. For public available projects you get unlimited build minutes and thats amazing. But for private repositories the number of build minutes is limited to the owners account. Even though 2000 build minutes are included in the free account plan, you might exceed this by having many repositories. Having a self hosted runner will give you an infite amount of build minutes.</description></item><item><title>Fix for kubernetes crd annotation too long problem</title><link>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/kubernetes-crd-annotation-too-long-fix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/kubernetes-crd-annotation-too-long-fix/</guid><description>Sometimes creating custom resource definitions (CRD) in kubernetes can be a bit challenging. Even with the help of helm charts there you may run in the following error while creating CRDs:
CustomResourceDefinition.apiextensions.k8s.io &amp;quot;runnerdeployments.actions.summerwind.dev&amp;quot; is invalid: metadata.annotations: Too long: must have at most 262144 bytes Tools like ArgoCD or HELM normally use &amp;ldquo;kubectl apply -f &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; to apply a yaml file. For CRDs with often very long description texts this can lead to the given error.</description></item><item><title>Cloudflare Tunnel for Kubernetes</title><link>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/cloudflare-tunnel-for-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/cloudflare-tunnel-for-kubernetes/</guid><description>Cloudflare offers a free to use Tunnel to connect a server e.g. behind a firewall with the cloudflare servers without opening ports. This can be very useful when operating a server at home or in office. To do that there is a client software called &amp;lsquo;cloudflared&amp;rsquo;. It is pretty easy to use that on your local computer to test that out like described here. Running inside a kubernetes cluster is a bit more tricky so in the following I give an example that should help.</description></item><item><title>How to setup ArgoCD to manage itself</title><link>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/setup-argocd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/setup-argocd/</guid><description>ArgoCD is in my opinion one of the best GitOps-Tools available. It checks a given Git-Repo and applies the configuration from there to a kubernetes cluster. The setup described in the ArgoCD-Guide using a single .yaml file is easy and straight forward. But from there you have to manually update and control ArgoCD whereas the rest of software will be controlled by ArgoCD. To also have ArgoCD update and configure itself it not much harder.</description></item><item><title>How to setup a k3s server with alpine linux</title><link>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/setup-home-k3s-server-with-alpine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 09:34:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/setup-home-k3s-server-with-alpine/</guid><description>Attention: This guide does NOT work on the raspberry pi!
I bought the new Macbook Pro with M1 Pro. The power of that device deprecates my Ryzen 3700X and so I decided to use that one as a server. I measured the power consumption with GPU (RX580) attached at about 90W and without at about 50W. So I used the GPU while installation and removed it afterwards.
As OS I decided to use Alpine Linux Extended version because it is very lightweight.</description></item><item><title>GRPC-Web example</title><link>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/grpc-web-example/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/grpc-web-example/</guid><description>There are dozens of articles out there describing the beneftits of GRPC over JSON. With this little example I wanted to evaluate the complexity of GRPC in combination with a frontend. Because GRPC always uses HTTP/2.0 and that is not supported by all browsers there is GRPC-Web which translates between &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; GRPC and and the web version for the browsers.
The project has three main components:
The GRPC-Server The GRPC-Web proxy The Angular frontend Protobuf file One benefit of GRPC is, that backend and frontend can generate their models and API&amp;rsquo;s from the common .</description></item><item><title>How to host a static website for free</title><link>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/how-to-host-a-website-for-free/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 09:34:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pcbaecker.com/posts/how-to-host-a-website-for-free/</guid><description>If you have a static website that should be served, there is no need for a hoster that costs money. You can use Google Clouds Object Storage or Github Pages like i did.
I use Hugo a static website generator to transform the raw text written in MarkDown into a static website. The transformation is handled automatically by Github Actions when i commit my local workspace to the Github repository.</description></item></channel></rss>